James Harmer

UX/UI Designer

I have been working as a designer since 2014, starting out as an apprentice, I learned my trade working for a small agency, gaining experience and a qualification in Graphic Design. Over the last 6 years I have progressed and honed my skills to specialise in UX and UI Design.

I am a quick learner with good communication skills and an eye for design and detail. I have experience working closely with clients and seeing projects through from start to finish. I am looking for the opportunity to improve my skills and work within a dynamic company in order to further develop a career as a User Experience and Interface Designer.

Work experience

Web Designer - Funeral Guide March 2019 - Present

As the company's sole Web Designer I have been responsible for transforming their online presence by rebranding and redesigning the website and creating a new website for Arranger.

Responsibilities:

- Redesigning and maintaining the Funeral Guide website
- Working on the user experience and interface design for Arranger.com
- Creating artwork and graphics for advertising on social media
- Working with print designers to implement new brand styles across all platforms.

Middleweight Digital Designer - Equiniti Data October 2017 - March 2019

Working as a Middleweight Digital Designer within a design department to create marketing materials for big name clients, as well as designing internal collateral for advertising campaigns and digital products.

Responsibilities:

- Following strict brand guidelines to create marketing campaigns for a range of clients including Santander, Legal & General and Tails.com
- Designing graphics to accompany marketing campaigns
- Working with HTML and CSS to develop web pages and responsive emails
- Designing documents for print such as flyers, postcards and booklets
- Researching and developing to be able to offer the latest HTML email technologies.







Digital Designer - Axminster Tools & Machinery March 2016 - September 2017

Working within a team of four Digital Designers creating email and website marketing materials to appeal to a wide customer base and drive sales.

Responsibilities:

- Working to a brief to create marketing material
- Building responsive HTML emails to send to customers
- Designing graphics to accompany marketing campaigns
- Working with HTML and CSS to develop landing pages.

Web Designer - Vector 7 July 2014 - March 2016

Working closely with clients to design and develop websites and online marketing materials in order to get them found on search engines for what they do and where they do it.

Responsibilities:

- Designing new websites to a client's brief
- Building user friendly websites for a range of businesses
- Improving the look and functionality of existing websites
- Conducting meetings with new and existing clients
- Interpreting analytical data to feedback to clients.

Education

Plymouth College of Art September 2014 - October 2015 BTech Level 3 in Graphic Design

The King's School Ottery St Mary September 2012 - July 2014 A Levels in ICT & Design Technology

The King's School Ottery St Mary September 2010 - June 2012 GCSE's in:

- English
- Maths
- Science
- ICT
- Design Technology
- Geography
- History

Personal information

Address:

9 Rye Park Cotleigh Honiton, Devon EX14 9HL

Contact details:

07903 354 879 jharmer220995@gmail.com

Date of birth: 22/09/1995 Nationality: British Driving licence: Yes



07903 354 879

